<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2026</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:08:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Illusion of Control: Capability Maturity Models and Red Teaming</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/capability-maturity-model-test-red-teaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/capability-maturity-model-test-red-teaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout my career I have been fascinated with quality assurance and testing, especially security testing and red teaming. One discussion that comes up frequently is how to measure the maturity of such programs and processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My answer is straight forward as there are already existing frameworks that can be leveraged, adjusted and borrowed from to fit the needs of offensive security programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are likely familiar or have at least heard of the &lt;strong&gt;Capability Maturity Model Integration&lt;/strong&gt; from Carnegie Mellon University. In particular &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capability_Maturity_Model_Integration&#34;&gt;CMMI&lt;/a&gt; defines five levels to measure software engineering processes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$3000 Bug Bounty Award from Mozilla for a successful targeted Credential Hunt</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/mozilla-bug-bounty-credential-hunt-phabricator-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/mozilla-bug-bounty-credential-hunt-phabricator-token/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I did some research on Firefox, specifically I was learning more about it&amp;rsquo;s remote debugging features. As part of that I was reading Bugzilla bug information and learned more about Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing I noticed reading up on details was that Mozilla uses &lt;strong&gt;Phabricator&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-phabricator&#34;&gt;What is Phabricator?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phabricator&lt;/strong&gt; is a collaborative web-based toolset for code reviews, checkins, bugs, work items, wiki, pastes, credentials and many other useful things. It was orginally developed by Facebook as far as I know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Exploitation: Abusing Chrome&#39;s debugging feature to observe and control browsing sessions remotely</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/chrome-spy-remote-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/chrome-spy-remote-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chrome&amp;rsquo;s remote debugging feature enables malware post-exploitation to gain access to cookies. Root privileges are not required. This is a pretty well-known and commonly used adversarial technique - at least since 2018 when &lt;strong&gt;Cookie Crimes&lt;/strong&gt; was released.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, remote debugging also &lt;strong&gt;allows observing user activities and sensitive personal information (aka spying on users) and controlling the browser from a remote computer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://embracethered.com/blog/images/2020/hacker.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hacker&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below screenshot shows a simulated attacker controlling the victim&amp;rsquo;s browser and navigating to &lt;em&gt;chrome://settings&lt;/em&gt; to inspect information:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunting for credentials and building a credential type reference catalog</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hunting-for-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 12:31:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hunting-for-credentials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adversaries are leveraging widely exposed clear text credentials to gain access to sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At times the term &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;harvesting credentials&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; is used when red teamers emulate these attacks - which is something that appears to be more opportunistic and I would &lt;strong&gt;propose that security teams start to actively hunt for credential exposure that can put their organization at risk&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; in case you are not yet doing that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;actively-hunting-for-credential-exposure&#34;&gt;Actively hunting for credential exposure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea of &lt;strong&gt;credential hunting is targeted and focused&lt;/strong&gt;, leveraging intelligence about systems and combing it with powerful search techniques to identify exposure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack Graphs - How to create and present them</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/conceptual-attack-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 21:00:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/conceptual-attack-graphs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;conceptual-attack-graphs&#34;&gt;Conceptual Attack Graphs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One question that I have gotten a few times about  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1838828869/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=wunderwuzzi-20&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1838828869&amp;amp;linkId=07bfd6b729fbc2b2904160e0e16c337f&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cybersecurity Attacks - Red Team Strategies&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is around the conceptual attack graphs in &amp;ldquo;Chapter 3, Measuring an Offensive Security Program&amp;rdquo;. Specifically, how I create them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post I will briefly go over some of the reasons for creating them, and also how I create them and share a template for others to use and adjust.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a graphic designer, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are better ways of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
