<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on wunderwuzzi blog</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on wunderwuzzi blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:00:33 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Race conditions when applying ACLs</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:00:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about a class of application security issues I ran across a few times over the years. In particular, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss race conditions when it comes to files with sensitive content and permissions.
Race conditions can allow an adversary to gain access to sensitive information on machines. Assume a system creates a file that contains sensitive information and afterwards applies permissions to lockdown that file.
Understanding the race condition Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a practical example seen in the wild a few times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory and MacOS</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</guid>
      <description>Interacting with Active Directory on the Mac Did you ever have to interact with Active Directory on a MAC?
If yes, this post might be interesting for you. I am pretty new to the Mac and basic things I know how to do on Windows need some research to figure out. This time around I explore Active Directory/LDAP Server interactions.
 First, there is the Directory Utility on MacOS which can be quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Leaks Your Alternate Email Addresses to Unauthenticated Users</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:51:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</guid>
      <description>The Google Login Flow leaks additional email account information to unauthenticated users. I discovered this in the Google Account Login flow while building KoiPhish.
Responsible Disclosure I reported this issue to Google and they looked into it and after a about 5 weeks of back and forth they decided that this is not an issue worth fixing. After asking if I can post about it publicly I got Google&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>