<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 08:00:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive BPF - Malicious bpftrace 🤯</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf-bpftrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 08:00:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf-bpftrace/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about Offensive BPF that I&amp;rsquo;m working on to learn about BPF to understand attacks and defenses, click the &amp;ldquo;ebpf&amp;rdquo; tag to see all relevant posts.
I&amp;rsquo;m learning BPF to understand how its use will impact offensive security, malware, and detection engineering.
One offsec idea that quickly comes to mind with BPF is to observe network traffic and act upon specific events. So, I wanted to see if/how bpftrace, a popular tool for running BPF programs, can be used to create potential backdoors, and what evidence to look for as defenders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive BPF! Getting started.</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few years eBPF has gained a lot of traction in the Linux community and beyond.
eBPF&amp;rsquo;s offensive usage is also slowly getting more attention. So, I decided to dive into the topic from a red teaming point of view to learn about it to raise awareness and share the journey.
Similar to the format of my Machine Learning Attack Series, there will be a serious of posts around BPF usage in offensive settings, and also how its misuse can be detected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abusing Application Layer Gateways (NAT Slipstreaming)</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/nat-slipstreaming-simplified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 23:00:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/nat-slipstreaming-simplified/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard about &amp;ldquo;NAT Slipstreaming&amp;rdquo; by Samy Kamkar. It&amp;rsquo;s an amazing technique that allows punching a hole in your routers firewall by just visiting a website.
The attack depends on the router having the Application Layer Gateway enabled. This gateway can be used by anyone inside your network to open a firewall port (totally by design). Protocols such as SIP (Session Initiation Protocol) use it.
What I will focus on in this post is the Application Layer Gateway (ALG) and SIP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race conditions when applying ACLs</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:00:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about a class of application security issues I ran across a few times over the years. In particular, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss race conditions when it comes to files with sensitive content and permissions.
Race conditions can allow an adversary to gain access to sensitive information on machines. Assume a system creates a file that contains sensitive information and afterwards applies permissions to lockdown that file.
Understanding the race condition Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a practical example seen in the wild a few times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2600 - The Hacker Quarterly - Pass the Cookie Article</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/2600-hacker-pass-the-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:48:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/2600-hacker-pass-the-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Pass the Cookie made it into the latest 2600 magazine! Very excited about this!
I was just walking around Capitol Hill and stopped by Ada&amp;rsquo;s Technical Books on 15th Avenue - a great coffee shop with lots of technical books. Right after walking in to grab a cup of tea, I saw the latest Hacker Quarterly. A few months back I submitted an article about &amp;ldquo;Pass the Cookie&amp;rdquo;, so I had to check, and the article got indeed published!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory and MacOS</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</guid>
      <description>Interacting with Active Directory on the Mac Did you ever have to interact with Active Directory on a MAC?
If yes, this post might be interesting for you. I am pretty new to the Mac and basic things I know how to do on Windows need some research to figure out. This time around I explore Active Directory/LDAP Server interactions.
 First, there is the Directory Utility on MacOS which can be quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Leaks Your Alternate Email Addresses to Unauthenticated Users</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:51:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</guid>
      <description>The Google Login Flow leaks additional email account information to unauthenticated users. I discovered this in the Google Account Login flow while building KoiPhish.
Responsible Disclosure I reported this issue to Google and they looked into it and after a about 5 weeks of back and forth they decided that this is not an issue worth fixing. After asking if I can post about it publicly I got Google&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>