<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>metrics on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/metrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in metrics on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:00:51 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/metrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gamifying Security with Red Team Scores</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/gamifying-red-team-security-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:00:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/gamifying-red-team-security-score/</guid>
      <description>Security metrics are an interesting topic.
Over the years I used &amp;ldquo;scores&amp;rdquo; as a tool to identify and shine light on problematic areas or highlight lack of engineering and security quality of certain teams.

A security score should not seen as an objective or absoulte measure, but it allows to compare systems with each other at a relative scale, and by sharing the score it makes people ask questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Teaming and Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-teaming-and-monte-carlo-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 11:23:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-teaming-and-monte-carlo-simulations/</guid>
      <description>Monte Carlo simulations can be a useful tool to uplevel your red teaming skills and provide a different and fresh perspective for highlighting, discussing and presenting findings.
Red teaming is about challenging an organization. This includes analyzing business processes and methodologies, including our own.
Obviously, using Monte Carlo simulations in the security realm is not my idea. I first ran across the idea in Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s book about measuring cybersecurity risk. Since then I have been thinking and playing around with applying these methods to security program&amp;rsquo;s, especially red teaming and threat modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phishing metrics - what to track?</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/phishing-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:26:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/phishing-stats/</guid>
      <description>The results of phishing campaigns are often not comparable with each other over time. Various security vendors and red teams use different tooling and techniques - which is totally fine.
However, I recommend requiring tracking a minimum set of metrics to be able to compare results over time.
Funny side facts: At times employees are messing with the red team, entering invalid creds for CISO or CEO and things along those lines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>