<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on wunderwuzzi blog</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on wunderwuzzi blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:04:29 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Husky AI walkthrough and threat model</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:04:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post I talked about learning resources for AI/ML. Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to dive into details on building a model and application we can perform security testing on.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll describe how I built Husky AI, an application that can identify if an image contains a husky or not.

If you watched the show Silicon Valley, you might find this quite funny.
In particular we will cover the following topics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the hang of machine learning</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/machine-learning-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/machine-learning-basics/</guid>
      <description>This year I have spent a lot of time studying machine learning and artificial intelligence.
To come up with good and useful attacks during operations, I figured it is time to learn the fundamentals and start using software, tools and algorithms. My goal was to build a couple of end to end machine learning systems from scratch, and then attack them.
This post describes my studying approach, materials, courses, and learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Teaming Telemetry Systems</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/attacking-telemetry-and-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/attacking-telemetry-and-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>These days business decisions and feature development often is influenced heavily by telemetry information. Telemetry is baked into the programs, services and applications we use.
Companies are hungry for telemetry because with machine learning and Deep Neural Networks &amp;ldquo;data is the new oil&amp;rdquo;.
Telemetry provides insights into how users use a particular system, what features they exercise, how they configure the system, what errors they trigger and what buttons they like clicking on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>