<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on wunderwuzzi blog</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on wunderwuzzi blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 21:02:16 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A machine learning journey</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/machine-learning-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 21:02:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/machine-learning-basics/</guid>
      <description>Over the last several months I have been busy studying machine learning and artificial intelligence.
To come up with good attacks, I figured it is time to learn the basics and start using software, tools and algorithms. My goal was to build a couple of end to end machine learning systems from scratch.
This post describes my studying approach, materials and learnings. I thought to share this information, in case there are others who are intersted to get started in this space and need some pointers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Teaming Telemetry Systems</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/attacking-telemetry-and-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/attacking-telemetry-and-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>These days business decisions and feature development often is influenced heavily by telemetry information. Telemetry is baked into the programs, services and applications we use.
Companies are hungry for telemetry because with machine learning and Deep Neural Networks &amp;ldquo;data is the new oil&amp;rdquo;.
Telemetry provides insights into how users use a particular system, what features they exercise, how they configure the system, what errors they trigger and what buttons they like clicking on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>