<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>appsec on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/appsec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in appsec on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 08:01:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/appsec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Web Application Security Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/web-application-security-fundamentals-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 08:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/web-application-security-fundamentals-video/</guid>
      <description>In this 25 minute video I&amp;rsquo;m explaining the foundations of Web Application Security.
The video covers the basic building blocks of web applications, such as HTML, HTTP, JavaScript and Cookies. Furthermore core web applications security concepts such as the Same-Origin Policy are discussed in detail.

The goal is to provide foundational knowledge to help grasp security vulnerabilities, such as XSS, CSRF, SQLi, tab-nabbing, etc. later on.
In the past I have trained and presented content like this to thousands of engineers at large organizations and cloud providers, hence its quite optimized for best learning and comprehension outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race conditions when applying ACLs</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:00:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about a class of application security issues I ran across a few times over the years. In particular, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss race conditions when it comes to files with sensitive content and permissions.
Race conditions can allow an adversary to gain access to sensitive information on machines. Assume a system creates a file that contains sensitive information and afterwards applies permissions to lockdown that file.
Understanding the race condition Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a practical example seen in the wild a few times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>