<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conference on wunderwuzzi blog</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conference on wunderwuzzi blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:00:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking neural networks - so we don&#39;t get stuck in the matrix</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hacking-the-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:00:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hacking-the-matrix/</guid>
      <description>For GrayHat 2020 I was asked to create a short intro video for my Red Team Village talk &amp;ldquo;Learning by doing: Building and breaking a machine learning system&amp;rdquo;.
So I put my green screen to good use and recorded this short clip for Red Team Village.
Here is the link to the clip on Twitter:

Hope you like it. :)
The talk will be October, 31st 2020.
Schedule: http://redteamvillage.io/schedule</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming up: Grayhat Red Team Village talk about hacking a machine learning system</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/accouncement-learning-by-doing-hacking-machine-lerning-grayhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 11:30:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/accouncement-learning-by-doing-hacking-machine-lerning-grayhat/</guid>
      <description>Excited to announce that I will be presenting at Grayhat - Red Team Village on October 31st 2020. The presentation is about my machine learning journey and how to build and break a machine learning system.
If you follow my blog, you can guess that there will be lots of discussion around &amp;ldquo;Husky AI&amp;rdquo;. The bits and pieces that make up a machine learning pipeline, and how to threat model such a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of the Shadowbunny - Using virtual machines to persist and evade detections</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-virtual-machine-red-teaming-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 20:00:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-virtual-machine-red-teaming-technique/</guid>
      <description>This was also presented at BSides Singapore 2020. The slides are here and YouTube link is here.
The origins of the Shadowbunny A few years ago, around 2016, I went on a relaxing two weeklong vacation. It was great to disconnect from work. I traveled to Austria, enjoying hiking in the mountains, and exploring Vienna.
When I came back to the office, the team had placed a giant bunny teddy into my chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of the Shadowbunny! at BSides Singapore</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-bsides-singapore-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-bsides-singapore-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>Excited to announce that I will be presenting at BSides Singapore this year.
The topic is adversarial usage of virtual machines during lateral movement. And we will also cover threat hunting and detection ideas.
I have been referring to this technique as the Shadowbunny over the years. :)
The conferences is on September 24th-25th, it will be all virtual and free to attend. Check out the BSidesSG 2020 website and schedule for other talks and details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pass the Cookie and Pivot to the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/passthecookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/passthecookie/</guid>
      <description>Web Applications and Services use cookies to authenticate sessions and users. An adversary can pivot from a compromised host to Web Applications and Internet Services by stealing authentication cookies from browsers and related processes. At the same time this technique bypasses most multi-factor authentication protocols.
The reason for this is that the final authentication token that the attacker steals is issued after all factors have been validated. Many users persist cookies that are valid for an extended period of time, even if the web application is not actively used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>