<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bugbounty on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/bugbounty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bugbounty on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:00:25 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/bugbounty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>$3000 Bug Bounty Award from Mozilla for a successful targeted Credential Hunt</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/mozilla-bug-bounty-credential-hunt-phabricator-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/mozilla-bug-bounty-credential-hunt-phabricator-token/</guid>
      <description>Last month I did some research on Firefox, specifically I was learning more about it&amp;rsquo;s remote debugging features. As part of that I was reading Bugzilla bug information and learned more about Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.
One thing I noticed reading up on details was that Mozilla uses Phabricator.
What is Phabricator? Phabricator is a collaborative web-based toolset for code reviews, checkins, bugs, work items, wiki, pastes, credentials and many other useful things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Leaks Your Alternate Email Addresses to Unauthenticated Users</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:51:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</guid>
      <description>The Google Login Flow leaks additional email account information to unauthenticated users. I discovered this in the Google Account Login flow while building KoiPhish.
Responsible Disclosure I reported this issue to Google and they looked into it and after a about 5 weeks of back and forth they decided that this is not an issue worth fixing. After asking if I can post about it publicly I got Google&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
