<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>video on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in video on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 08:10:12 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Anatomy of a compromise</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/video-anatomy-of-a-compromise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 08:10:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/video-anatomy-of-a-compromise/</guid>
      <description>Cybersecurity breaches follow common patterns and stages - from an initial Beachhead to accomplishing Objectives.
This video gives an overview of the anatomy of a compromise:

Cheers.
@wunderwuzzi23</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Understanding Image Scaling Attacks</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/video-image-scaling-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/video-image-scaling-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Today you are in for a special treat. Did you know that an adversary can hide a smaller image within a larger one?
This video demonstrates how a small image becomes magically visible when the computer resizes the large image, and also how to mitigate the vulnerability.

This is possible when vulnerable code uses insecure interpolation.
If you like this one check out the overall Machine Learning Attack Series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: What is Tabnabbing?</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/what-is-tab-nabbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 10:10:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/what-is-tab-nabbing/</guid>
      <description>Tabnabbing is a web application security vulnerability that can be used to perform phishing attacks, so its important to be aware of it as a developer and penetration tester.
It is easy to mitigate and in this short video we cover both attacks and mitigations.

Thanks for reading and happy hacking!
@wunderwuzzi23</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Web Application Security Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/web-application-security-fundamentals-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 08:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/web-application-security-fundamentals-video/</guid>
      <description>In this 25 minute video I&amp;rsquo;m explaining the foundations of Web Application Security.
The video covers the basic building blocks of web applications, such as HTML, HTTP, JavaScript and Cookies. Furthermore core web applications security concepts such as the Same-Origin Policy are discussed in detail.

The goal is to provide foundational knowledge to help grasp security vulnerabilities, such as XSS, CSRF, SQLi, tab-nabbing, etc. later on.
In the past I have trained and presented content like this to thousands of engineers at large organizations and cloud providers, hence its quite optimized for best learning and comprehension outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>