<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wunderwuzzi blog</title>
    <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on wunderwuzzi blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; WUNDERWUZZI 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 11:51:45 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 11:51:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/using-hugo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BashSpray - Simple Password Spray Bash Script</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/bash-spray-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 21:58:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/bash-spray-password/</guid>
      <description>One thing every red team should attempt early on and regularly is to perform some password spray testing across their organization to identify and help remediate usage of weak passwords.
In the past I have done this on Windows a lot, but now I built a simple version for it for Bash to run it also from a Mac.
Check it out: Bash Spray
Ideally, a script like bashspray.sh is integrated into your response pipelines, and SOC, Blue Team as well as account owner get notified - so they change their password right away, and any SOC investigation can be performed if necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory and MacOS</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</guid>
      <description>Interacting with Active Directory on the Mac Did you ever have to interact with Active Directory on a MAC?
If yes, this post might be interesting for you. I am pretty new to the Mac and basic things I know how to do on Windows need some research to figure out. This time around I explore Active Directory/LDAP Server interactions.
 First, there is the Directory Utility on MacOS which can be quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Leaks Your Alternate Email Addresses to Unauthenticated Users</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:51:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</guid>
      <description>The Google Login Flow leaks additional email account information to unauthenticated users. I discovered this in the Google Account Login flow while building KoiPhish.
Responsible Disclosure I reported this issue to Google and they looked into it and after a about 5 weeks of back and forth they decided that this is not an issue worth fixing. After asking if I can post about it publicly I got Google&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyrebird - Hack the hacker (and take a picture)</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/lyrebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 21:48:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/lyrebird/</guid>
      <description>The idea for Lyrebird came from observing that sometimes when someone forgets lock their workstation, someone else might mess with their computer. Since I wanted to learn more on how to program a webcam and take pictures - I figured why not create a little tool that takes a screenshot and uses the webcam to take pictures of anyone that interacts with the computer while I&amp;rsquo;m gone.
The way this work is simple, start Lyrebird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KoiPhish - The Beautiful Phishing Proxy</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/koiphish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 21:40:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/koiphish/</guid>
      <description>KoiPhish is a simple yet beautiful relay proxy idea.
The idea for this little project goes back many years. Since I started learning Golang I figured it would be good exercise to finally go ahead an implement it. So, last December during the 35C3 (which is always inspiring congress) I wrote it up.
It relays requests a client makes to the KoiPish to the actual target and responses are sent back to the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McPivot and useful LLDB commands</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/lldbbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 21:34:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/lldbbasics/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of useful notes when dealing with Macs. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty new to Macs and there might be other, better solutions to the challenges I had to sovle but these worked for me and I&amp;rsquo;m learning. :)
Pivoting between accounts and keychain issues After pivoting on a target host and elevating to root it seems not possible to gain access to other keychains easily. It requires to know the password of the other account still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pass the Cookie and Pivot to the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/passthecookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wunderwuzzi23.github.io/blog/posts/passthecookie/</guid>
      <description>Web Applications and Services use cookies to authenticate sessions and users. An adversary can pivot from a compromised host to Web Applications and Internet Services by stealing authentication cookies from browsers and related processes. At the same time this technique bypasses most multi-factor authentication protocols.
The reason for this is that the final authentication token that the attacker steals is issued after all factors have been validated. Many users persist cookies that are valid for an extended period of time, even if the web application is not actively used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>