<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wunderwuzzi blog</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on wunderwuzzi blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:00:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking neural networks - so we don&#39;t get stuck in the matrix</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hacking-the-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:00:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hacking-the-matrix/</guid>
      <description>For GrayHat 2020 I was asked to create a short intro video for my Red Team Village talk &amp;ldquo;Learning by doing: Building and breaking a machine learning system&amp;rdquo;.
So I put my green screen to good use and recorded this short clip for Red Team Village.
Here is the link to the clip on Twitter:

Hope you like it. :)
The talk will be October, 31st 2020.
Schedule: http://redteamvillage.io/schedule</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does an offensive security team actually do?</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-team-offensive-security-service-offerings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-team-offensive-security-service-offerings/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of discussion around terms such as red team, attack team, pentest, adversarial engineering or offensive security team and similar ones.
I typically stay away from the (sometimes passionate) discussions that ensue whenever this topic comes up.
Personally, I think a good strategy is to define programs and teams who operate in this space by what services the team (or teams) provide(s) to the organization.
The business groups, blue team, developers, engineers, employees and clients are the customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE 2020-16977: VS Code Python Extension Remote Code Execution</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/cve-2020-16977-vscode-microsoft-python-extension-remote-code-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:35:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/cve-2020-16977-vscode-microsoft-python-extension-remote-code-execution/</guid>
      <description>While building &amp;ldquo;Husky AI&amp;rdquo; I started working a lot with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s VS Code Python extension. It is a super convinient way to edit Jupyter Notebooks. I just use VS Code&amp;rsquo;s Remote SSH feature to get to my Linux host and work on modeling and testing there.
When threat modeling &amp;ldquo;Husky AI&amp;rdquo; I identified backdooring of third party libraries and development tools as a potential issue to be aware of.
So finding security issues in the tools is naturally something I am keeping an eye on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Attack Series: Stealing a model file</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-model-stealing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 05:50:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-model-stealing/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence. Click on the blog tag &amp;ldquo;huskyai&amp;rdquo; to see related posts.
 Overview: How Husky AI was built, threat modeled and operationalized Attacks: The attacks I want to investigate, learn about, and try out  We talked about creating adversarial examples and &amp;ldquo;backdoor images&amp;rdquo; for Husky AI before. One thing that we noticed was that an adversary with model access can very efficiently come up with adversarial examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming up: Grayhat Red Team Village talk about hacking a machine learning system</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/accouncement-learning-by-doing-hacking-machine-lerning-grayhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 11:30:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/accouncement-learning-by-doing-hacking-machine-lerning-grayhat/</guid>
      <description>Excited to announce that I will be presenting at Grayhat - Red Team Village on October 31st 2020. The presentation is about my machine learning journey and how to build and break a machine learning system.
If you follow my blog, you can guess that there will be lots of discussion around &amp;ldquo;Husky AI&amp;rdquo;. The bits and pieces that make up a machine learning pipeline, and how to threat model such a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of the Shadowbunny - Using virtual machines to persist and evade detections</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-virtual-machine-red-teaming-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 20:00:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-virtual-machine-red-teaming-technique/</guid>
      <description>This was also presented at BSides Singapore 2020. The slides are here and YouTube link is here.
The origins of the Shadowbunny A few years ago, around 2016, I went on a relaxing two weeklong vacation. It was great to disconnect from work. I traveled to Austria, enjoying hiking in the mountains, and exploring Vienna.
When I came back to the office, the team had placed a giant bunny teddy into my chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participating in the Microsoft Machine Learning Security Evasion Competition - Bypassing malware models by signing binaries</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/microsoft-machine-learning-security-evasion-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 14:00:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/microsoft-machine-learning-security-evasion-competition/</guid>
      <description>This year one of my goals was to learn about machine learning and artificial intelligence.
I wrote about my journey before - including what classes I took and books I read, the models and systems I built and operationalized, threat modeling it to learn about practical attacks and defenses. My goal is to be knowledge enough in the AI/ML space enough to be able to help bridge the gap between research and operational red teaming - by doing practical things with life systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Attack Series: Backdooring models</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-backdoor-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:59:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-backdoor-model/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence. Click on the blog tag &amp;ldquo;huskyai&amp;rdquo; to see related posts.
 Overview: How Husky AI was built, threat modeled and operationalized Attacks: The attacks I want to investigate, learn about, and try out Mitigations: Ways to prevent and detect the backdooring threat  During threat modeling we identified that an adversary might tamper with model files. From a technical point of view this means an adversary gained access to the model file used in production and is able overwrite it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Attack Series: Perturbations to misclassify existing images</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-attack-perturbation-external/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 12:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-attack-perturbation-external/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence. Click on the blog tag &amp;ldquo;huskyai&amp;rdquo; to see related posts.
 Overview: How Husky AI was built, threat modeled and operationalized Attacks: The attacks I want to investigate, learn about, and try out  The previous post covered some neat smart fuzzing techniques to improve generation of fake husky images.
The goal of this post is to take an existing image of the plush bunny below, modify it and have the model identify it as a husky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Attack Series: Smart brute forcing</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-attack-smart-fuzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 09:04:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-attack-smart-fuzz/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence. Click on the blog tag &amp;ldquo;huskyai&amp;rdquo; to see related posts. There are the two main sections of the series - more content will be added over time:
 Overview: How Husky AI was built, threat modeled and operationalized Attacks: The attacks I want to investigate, learn about, and try out  The previous post covered basic tests to trick the image recognition model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Attack Series: Brute forcing images to find incorrect predictions</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-attack-bruteforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 09:09:09 -0909</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-machine-learning-attack-bruteforce/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence. Click on the blog tag &amp;ldquo;huskyai&amp;rdquo; to see related posts.
The previous four posts explained the architecture and how Husky AI was built, threat modeled and deployed. Now it’s time to start the attacks and build mitigations. The appendix in this post shows all the attacks I want to research and perform in this series over the next few weeks/months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threat modeling a machine learning system</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-threat-modeling-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-threat-modeling-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence. Click on the blog tag &amp;ldquo;huskyai&amp;rdquo; to see all the posts, or visit the overview section.
In the previous post we walked through the steps required to gather training data, build and test a model to build &amp;ldquo;Husky AI&amp;rdquo;.
This post is all about threat modeling the system to identify scenarios for attacks which we will perform in the upcoming posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLOps - Operationalizing the machine learning model</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-mlops-operationalize-the-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 08:00:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-mlops-operationalize-the-model/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence.
In the previous post we walked through the steps required to gather training data, build and test a model.
In this post we dive into &amp;ldquo;Operationalizing&amp;rdquo; the model. The scenario is the creation of Husky AI and my experiences and learnings from that.
Part 3 - Operationalizing the Husky AI model This actually took much longer than planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Husky AI: Building a machine learning system</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-building-the-machine-learning-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 12:04:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-building-the-machine-learning-model/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence.
In the previous post we described the overall machine learning pipeline.
In this post we dive into the technical details on how I built and trained the machine learning model for Husky AI.
After reading this you should have a good understanding around the technical steps involved in building a machine learning system, and also some thoughts around what can be attacked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The machine learning pipeline and attacks</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:04:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/husky-ai-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about machine learning and artificial intelligence.
In the previous post I talked about good resources for learning more about artificial intelligence and machine learning in general, and how I started my journey in this space.
The next few posts will be about Husky AI.
What is Husky AI? Husky AI allows a user to upload an image, and get an answer back if the image contains a husky or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the hang of machine learning</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/machine-learning-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/machine-learning-basics/</guid>
      <description>This year I have spent a lot of time studying machine learning and artificial intelligence.
To come up with good and useful attacks during operations, I figured it is time to learn the fundamentals and start using software, tools and algorithms. My goal was to build a couple of end to end machine learning systems from scratch, and then attack them.
This post describes my studying approach, materials, courses, and learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of the Shadowbunny! at BSides Singapore</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-bsides-singapore-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-bsides-singapore-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>Excited to announce that I will be presenting at BSides Singapore this year.
The topic is adversarial usage of virtual machines during lateral movement. And we will also cover threat hunting and detection ideas.
I have been referring to this technique as the Shadowbunny over the years. :)
The conferences is on September 24th-25th, it will be all virtual and free to attend. Check out the BSidesSG 2020 website and schedule for other talks and details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race conditions when applying ACLs</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:00:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/applying-acls-and-race-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about a class of application security issues I ran across a few times over the years. In particular, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss race conditions when it comes to files with sensitive content and permissions.
Race conditions can allow an adversary to gain access to sensitive information on machines. Assume a system creates a file that contains sensitive information and afterwards applies permissions to lockdown that file.
Understanding the race condition Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a practical example seen in the wild a few times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Teaming Telemetry Systems</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/attacking-telemetry-and-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 13:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/attacking-telemetry-and-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>These days business decisions and feature development often is influenced heavily by telemetry information. Telemetry is baked into the programs, services and applications we use.
Companies are hungry for telemetry because with machine learning and Deep Neural Networks &amp;ldquo;data is the new oil&amp;rdquo;.
Telemetry provides insights into how users use a particular system, what features they exercise, how they configure the system, what errors they trigger and what buttons they like clicking on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusion of Control: Capability Maturity Models and Red Teaming</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/capability-maturity-model-test-red-teaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/capability-maturity-model-test-red-teaming/</guid>
      <description>Throughout my career I have been fascinated with quality assurance and testing, especially security testing and red teaming. One discussion that comes up frequently is how to measure the maturity of such programs and processes.
My answer is straight forward as there are already existing frameworks that can be leveraged, adjusted and borrowed from to fit the needs of offensive security programs.
You are likely familiar or have at least heard of the Capability Maturity Model Integration from Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivated Intruder - Red Teaming for Privacy!</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-teaming-for-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 10:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-teaming-for-privacy/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will discuss some testing techniques for internal red teams to identify privacy issues in services and infrastructure, most importantly a simple three step approach that might uncover interesting results.
Background story First, let me share a story from the past. When I did my master&amp;rsquo;s I built an app that performs end to end encryption of Facebook posts. This means that only the intended audience for which your posts were encrypted for can decipher the posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox - Debugger Client for Cookie Access</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/firefox-cookie-debug-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 11:00:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/firefox-cookie-debug-client/</guid>
      <description>Finally I got to writing some basic tooling for invoking the Firefox debugging API to send commands to the browser and read the responses. This can be useful for grabbing cookies in the post-exploitation phase.
It works for Windows and macOS, should also work on Linux.

This technique is probably most useful when we don&amp;rsquo;t have root or the user&amp;rsquo;s credentials to decrypt cookies or can&amp;rsquo;t attach a regular debugger to the browser process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remotely debugging Firefox instances</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/cookies-on-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/cookies-on-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Previously I talked about remotely debugging Chrome, and we also covered the latest Microsoft Edge browser along the way.
These features allow an adversary to gain access to authentication tokens and cookies. See MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK Technique T1539: Steal Web Session Cookie as well for this.
What about Firefox? For a while I was wondering if (my favorite) browser Firefox has such debugging features as well, and how one could detect malware trying to exploit it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing port-proxying and port-forwarding on Windows</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/windows-port-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 20:18:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/windows-port-forward/</guid>
      <description>A technique on Windows that is less known is how to do basic port-proxying.
Proxying ports is useful when a process binds on one (maybe only the local) interface and you want to expose that endpoint on another network interface.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have an existing process that listens only on the loopback interface, and you want to expose it remotely. Or there are two network interfaces and you want expose traffic from one to the other (maybe some evil persistence for port 3389) - or think of basic pivoting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blast from the past: Cross Site Scripting on the AWS Console</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/aws-xss-cross-site-scripting-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/aws-xss-cross-site-scripting-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Bug Bounty! Great news: Amazon is now offering bounties via a security vulnerabiltiy research program
Bad news: AWS is out of scope!
When I read this I remembered that a few years ago I found persistent Cross-Site-Scripting on the AWS Console.
This post is a write up on how I found the XSS back then, techniques I used and how they evolved over the years and Amazon&amp;rsquo;s response.
AWS Console and Cross Site Scripting The story is that I had just created an AWS account and started using the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedspot ranked &#39;Embrace the Red&#39; one of the top 15 pentest blogs</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/embrace-the-red-one-of-top-15-pentest-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 23:45:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/embrace-the-red-one-of-top-15-pentest-blogs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited that Feedspot ranked this blog (Embrace the Red) the number #10 pentest blog out there.
Subscribe and check-in regularly for new content related to offensive security engineering, penetration testing and red teaming.
You can also follow me on Twitter @wunderwuzzi23.
Cheers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using built-in OS indexing features for credential hunting</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/invoke-windowssearch-credential-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:00:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/invoke-windowssearch-credential-hunt/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago we discussed the importance of performing active credential hunting for your organization.
This is to ensure clear text credentials in widely accessible locations and source code are identified before an adversary gets a hold of them.
In this post we will explore using built-in operating system indexing features to search for information on machines quickly.
Many of us use the indexing features (like Windows Search and Spotlight) daily via the UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadowbunny article published in the PenTest Magazine</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-ttp-pentest-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 18:42:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/shadowbunny-ttp-pentest-magazine/</guid>
      <description>The Shadowbunny TTP in the PenTest Magazine The latest edition of the PenTest Magazine features an article of mine about using virtual machines (VMs) during lateral movement to establish persistence and evade detections.
A few years back when I came up with the idea of using VMs for lateral movement during red teaming, I called it the Shadowbunny TTP and that name stuck around in my head. There is more info in the article around the origin of the name also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting system owners in Security Bug Jail</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/bugjail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 10:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/bugjail/</guid>
      <description>Some organization have this interesting concept of a bug jail to prevent new feature development when there are too many existing flaws in the system.
For instance, if an engineer has 5 or more bugs assigned they aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to work on anything else but fixing their bugs.
What is the Security Bug Jail? A security bug jail goes along the same lines. The owner of a system can never have more than a certain upper limit of active security bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Teaming and Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-teaming-and-monte-carlo-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 11:23:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-teaming-and-monte-carlo-simulations/</guid>
      <description>Monte Carlo simulations can be a useful tool to uplevel your red teaming skills and provide a different and fresh perspective for highlighting, discussing and presenting findings.
Red teaming is about challenging an organization. This includes analyzing business processes and methodologies, including our own.
Obviously, using Monte Carlo simulations in the security realm is not my idea. I first ran across the idea in Hubbard&amp;rsquo;s book about measuring cybersecurity risk. Since then I have been thinking and playing around with applying these methods to security program&amp;rsquo;s, especially red teaming and threat modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phishing metrics - what to track?</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/phishing-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:26:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/phishing-stats/</guid>
      <description>The results of phishing campaigns are often not comparable with each other over time. Various security vendors and red teams use different tooling and techniques - which is totally fine.
However, I recommend requiring tracking a minimum set of metrics to be able to compare results over time.
Funny side facts: At times employees are messing with the red team, entering invalid creds for CISO or CEO and things along those lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$3000 Bug Bounty Award from Mozilla for a successful targeted Credential Hunt</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/mozilla-bug-bounty-credential-hunt-phabricator-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/mozilla-bug-bounty-credential-hunt-phabricator-token/</guid>
      <description>Last month I did some research on Firefox, specifically I was learning more about it&amp;rsquo;s remote debugging features. As part of that I was reading Bugzilla bug information and learned more about Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.
One thing I noticed reading up on details was that Mozilla uses Phabricator.
What is Phabricator? Phabricator is a collaborative web-based toolset for code reviews, checkins, bugs, work items, wiki, pastes, credentials and many other useful things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Crimes and the new Microsoft Edge Browser</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/cookie-crimes-on-mirosoft-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 01:00:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/cookie-crimes-on-mirosoft-edge/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting Cookie Crimes In 2018 @mangopdf described &amp;ldquo;Cookie Crimes&amp;rdquo;, which is great research around Chrome&amp;rsquo;s remote debugging feature that allows adversaries and malware to gain access to cookies quite convienently during post-exploitation.
The original research is published here, and it still works today.
The new Microsoft Edge browser and Chromium Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s latest Edge browser is based on the same code, Chromium. I guess, you already know where this is going now&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Exploitation: Abusing Chrome&#39;s debugging feature to observe and control browsing sessions remotely</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/chrome-spy-remote-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/chrome-spy-remote-control/</guid>
      <description>Chrome&amp;rsquo;s remote debugging feature enables malware post-exploitation to gain access to cookies. Root privileges are not required. This is a pretty well-known and commonly used adversarial technique - at least since 2018 when Cookie Crimes was released.
However, remote debugging also allows observing user activities and sensitive personal information (aka spying on users) and controlling the browser from a remote computer.
Below screenshot shows a simulated attacker controlling the victim&amp;rsquo;s browser and navigating to chrome://settings to inspect information:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunting for credentials and building a credential type reference catalog</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hunting-for-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 12:31:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/hunting-for-credentials/</guid>
      <description>Adversaries are leveraging widely exposed clear text credentials to gain access to sensitive information.
At times the term &amp;ldquo;harvesting credentials&amp;rdquo; is used when red teamers emulate these attacks - which is something that appears to be more opportunistic and I would propose that security teams start to actively hunt for credential exposure that can put their organization at risk &amp;ndash; in case you are not yet doing that.
Actively hunting for credential exposure The idea of credential hunting is targeted and focused, leveraging intelligence about systems and combing it with powerful search techniques to identify exposure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attack Graphs - How to create and present them</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/conceptual-attack-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 21:00:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/conceptual-attack-graphs/</guid>
      <description>Conceptual Attack Graphs One question that I have gotten a few times about &amp;ldquo;Cybersecurity Attacks - Red Team Strategies&amp;rdquo; is around the conceptual attack graphs in &amp;ldquo;Chapter 3, Measuring an Offensive Security Program&amp;rdquo;. Specifically, how I create them.
In this post I will briefly go over some of the reasons for creating them, and also how I create them and share a template for others to use and adjust.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a graphic designer, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are better ways of doing this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Attacks - Red Team Strategies has been released.</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/book-cybersecurity-attacks-red-team-strategies-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:01:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/book-cybersecurity-attacks-red-team-strategies-released/</guid>
      <description>Announcement After countless evenings and weekends in coffee shops, and multiple vacations with the laptop, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce that my first book has been published. It took 18 months from writing the first words (at Victrola Coffee Roasters on Capitol Hill by the way) to finishing this project just a few days ago.

Looking back its amazing how this all came together. The first intial draft had 100 pages, and in the end it ended up being 524 pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2600 - The Hacker Quarterly - Pass the Cookie Article</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/2600-hacker-pass-the-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 15:48:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/2600-hacker-pass-the-cookie/</guid>
      <description>Pass the Cookie made it into the latest 2600 magazine! Very excited about this!
I was just walking around Capitol Hill and stopped by Ada&amp;rsquo;s Technical Books on 15th Avenue - a great coffee shop with lots of technical books. Right after walking in to grab a cup of tea, I saw the latest Hacker Quarterly. A few months back I submitted an article about &amp;ldquo;Pass the Cookie&amp;rdquo;, so I had to check, and the article got indeed published!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Application Security Principles Revisited</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/importance-security-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 17:03:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/importance-security-principles/</guid>
      <description>Final Year Project - Web Application Security Principles About 18 years ago I worked on the final year project for my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science. I had just gotten interested in security and was learning about security principles.
The title of the project was &amp;ldquo;Web Application Security Principles - Designing Secure Web Based Enterprise Solutions&amp;rdquo;.
Looking back, a really cool thing was that I had just started working at Microsoft as an Associate Development Consultant and was bold enough to send the paper last minute over to Michael Howard - who responded and indeed reviewed it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust and Disabling Remote Management Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/zero-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 14:08:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/zero-trust/</guid>
      <description>This post highlights a simple mitigation to improve the security posture of your organization. The idea is to, by practical means, limit attack surface and prevent spreading of automated malware, as well as limiting lateral movement by adversaries.
Network security over the last 15 years Malware can spread fast and damage businesses at scale.
SQL Slammer [1] and WannaCry [2] are two well-known cases that showed how quickly and damaging this can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Cybersecurity Attacks - Red Team Strategies</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/book-cybersecurity-attacks-red-team-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 17:09:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/book-cybersecurity-attacks-red-team-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Excited to announce the book that I have been working on:
Cybersecurity Attacks - Red Team Strategies
Learn about the foundational tactics, techniques and procedures to elevate your red teaming skills and enhance the overall security posture of your organization by leveraging homefield advantage. 
Contents and Background Red Team Strategies covers aspects that are not as commonly discussed in literature, including chapters around building and managing a pen test team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MITRE ATT&amp;CK Update for Cloud and cookies!</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/mitreattackupdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 10:56:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/mitreattackupdate/</guid>
      <description>MITRE just updated the ATT&amp;amp;CK Framework to include Cloud TTPs.
The update includes techniques for stealing cookies from machines and using them for lateral movement. These are the two techniques I helped contribute to the matrix:
 Credential Access - Steal Web Session Cookie Lateral Movement - Web Session Cookie  It was exciting experience to collaborate with MITRE and contribute on this. And kinda cool to see the Pass the Cookie work referenced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coinbase under attack and cookie theft</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/coinbase-hack-cookie-theft-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 13:25:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/coinbase-hack-cookie-theft-pass/</guid>
      <description>Recently Coinbase published a well written blog post on how they were under attack. The adversaries exploite Firefox 0-days. Details can be found here. One intersting aspect is the following:
 &amp;ldquo;We have also observed the attackers specifically target cloud services, e.g. gmail and others, via browser session token theft via direct access to browser datastores. This activity also offers the opportunity for behavior-based detection, as relatively few processes should be directly accessing those files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity - Homefield Advantage</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/homefield-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 18:46:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/homefield-advantage/</guid>
      <description>No one should beat your security team on the homefield! For several years I have been using the term Homefield Advantage in the context of running a security program, especially in regards to certain aspects of red teaming. Homefield Advantage describes well what a mature security program has to realize and leverage.
Wikipedia describes &amp;ldquo;home advantage&amp;rdquo; in team sports and highlights some of the benefits:
 &amp;ldquo;This benefit has been attributed to psychological effects supporting fans have on the competitors or referees; to psychological or physiological advantages of playing near home in familiar situations; to the disadvantages away teams suffer from changing time zones or climates, or from the rigors of travel; and, in some sports, to specific rules that favor the home team directly or indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now using Hugo for the blog</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 11:51:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Today I finalized moving the blog and publishing to Hugo. It was pretty straight forward and I decided to move things into a master branch on github, and publish via the docs/ folder features of Github pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BashSpray - Simple Password Spray Bash Script</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/bash-spray-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 21:58:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/bash-spray-password/</guid>
      <description>One thing every red team should attempt early on and regularly is to perform some password spray testing across their organization to identify and help remediate usage of weak passwords.
In the past I have done this on Windows a lot, but now I built a simple version for it for Bash to run it also from a Mac.
Check it out: Bash Spray
Ideally, a script like bashspray.sh is integrated into your response pipelines, and SOC, Blue Team as well as account owner get notified - so they change their password right away, and any SOC investigation can be performed if necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory and MacOS</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/active-directory-and-macos/</guid>
      <description>Interacting with Active Directory on the Mac Did you ever have to interact with Active Directory on a MAC?
If yes, this post might be interesting for you. I am pretty new to the Mac and basic things I know how to do on Windows need some research to figure out. This time around I explore Active Directory/LDAP Server interactions.
 First, there is the Directory Utility on MacOS which can be quite useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Leaks Your Alternate Email Addresses to Unauthenticated Users</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:51:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/google-email-leak/</guid>
      <description>The Google Login Flow leaks additional email account information to unauthenticated users. I discovered this in the Google Account Login flow while building KoiPhish.
Responsible Disclosure I reported this issue to Google and they looked into it and after a about 5 weeks of back and forth they decided that this is not an issue worth fixing. After asking if I can post about it publicly I got Google&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyrebird - Hack the hacker (and take a picture)</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/lyrebird/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 21:48:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/lyrebird/</guid>
      <description>The idea for Lyrebird came from observing that sometimes when someone forgets lock their workstation, someone else might mess with their computer. Since I wanted to learn more on how to program a webcam and take pictures - I figured why not create a little tool that takes a screenshot and uses the webcam to take pictures of anyone that interacts with the computer while I&amp;rsquo;m gone.
The way this work is simple, start Lyrebird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KoiPhish - The Beautiful Phishing Proxy</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/koiphish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 21:40:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/koiphish/</guid>
      <description>KoiPhish is a simple yet beautiful relay proxy idea.
The idea for this little project goes back many years. Since I started learning Golang I figured it would be good exercise to finally go ahead an implement it. So, last December during the 35C3 (which is always inspiring congress) I wrote it up.
It relays requests a client makes to the KoiPish to the actual target and responses are sent back to the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McPivot and useful LLDB commands</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/lldbbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 21:34:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/lldbbasics/</guid>
      <description>Just a list of useful notes when dealing with Macs. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty new to Macs and there might be other, better solutions to the challenges I had to sovle but these worked for me and I&amp;rsquo;m learning. :)
Pivoting between accounts and keychain issues After pivoting on a target host and elevating to root it seems not possible to gain access to other keychains easily. It requires to know the password of the other account still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pass the Cookie and Pivot to the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/passthecookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/passthecookie/</guid>
      <description>Web Applications and Services use cookies to authenticate sessions and users. An adversary can pivot from a compromised host to Web Applications and Internet Services by stealing authentication cookies from browsers and related processes. At the same time this technique bypasses most multi-factor authentication protocols.
The reason for this is that the final authentication token that the attacker steals is issued after all factors have been validated. Many users persist cookies that are valid for an extended period of time, even if the web application is not actively used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>