<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Program on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/program/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Program on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 08:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/program/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Somewhere today a company is breached</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/somewhere-today-a-company-is-breached/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/somewhere-today-a-company-is-breached/</guid>
      <description>This rather lengthy post goes into reasons for having an offensive security program and in particular, on how a red team can help improve the immune system of your organization. This is the high-level outline of the post:&#xA;Security breaches cannot be entirely prevented Implications of a breach Automated malware can hit your organization at any time Security investments - run as fast as you can, just to stay in place The immune system of your organization Embracing the red With regular cadence companies are compromised and suffer breaches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does an offensive security team actually do?</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-team-offensive-security-service-offerings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2020/red-team-offensive-security-service-offerings/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of discussion around terms such as red team, attack team, pentest, adversarial engineering or offensive security team and similar ones.&#xA;I typically stay away from the (sometimes passionate) discussions that ensue whenever this topic comes up.&#xA;Personally, I think a good strategy is to define programs and teams who operate in this space by what services the team (or teams) provide(s) to the organization.&#xA;The business groups, blue team, developers, engineers, employees and clients are the customers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
