<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardware on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardware on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 23:58:26 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flipper Zero - Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2022/flipper-zero-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 23:58:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2022/flipper-zero-intro/</guid>
      <description>After a bit of a delay my Flipper Zero finally arrived in the mail. If you are not familiar with Flipper Zero at all, check out the original Kickstarter page from a few years back.
This is what the package looks like after opening. It contains the device, a USB cable, a quick start manual (mostly pointing you to the Flipper Zero website), and a Flipper &amp;ldquo;Hack the planet&amp;rdquo; sticker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtag hacks - scanning via browser, removing speaker and data exfiltration</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/airtag-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 08:00:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/airtag-hacks/</guid>
      <description>Until the Apple Airtag came out a few months ago I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really looked into the tag tracking market. Turns out there were already quite a lot of offerings available before Apple joined the market, most notably Tile.
However, I wanted to try out the Airtag and ended up ordering a few.
This post will explore three things:
 Removing the speaker of my Airtag Using Browser APIs to scan for Airtags (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an iPhone but someone tries to stalk you this might be handy) Explore data exfiltration via Airtags and Apple&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Find My&amp;rdquo; network  By the way, when you order your Airtags online you can customize them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
