<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ebpf on Embrace The Red</title>
    <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/ebpf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ebpf on Embrace The Red</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) WUNDERWUZZI 2018-2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 08:00:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://embracethered.com/blog/tags/ebpf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive BPF - Malicious bpftrace 🤯</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf-bpftrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 08:00:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf-bpftrace/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series about Offensive BPF that I&amp;rsquo;m working on to learn about BPF to understand attacks and defenses, click the &amp;ldquo;ebpf&amp;rdquo; tag to see all relevant posts.
I&amp;rsquo;m learning BPF to understand how its use will impact offensive security, malware, and detection engineering.
One offsec idea that quickly comes to mind with BPF is to observe network traffic and act upon specific events. So, I wanted to see if/how bpftrace, a popular tool for running BPF programs, can be used to create potential backdoors, and what evidence to look for as defenders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive BPF! Getting started.</title>
      <link>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://embracethered.com/blog/posts/2021/offensive-bpf/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few years eBPF has gained a lot of traction in the Linux community and beyond.
eBPF&amp;rsquo;s offensive usage is also slowly getting more attention. So, I decided to dive into the topic from a red teaming point of view to learn about it to raise awareness and share the journey.
Similar to the format of my Machine Learning Attack Series, there will be a serious of posts around BPF usage in offensive settings, and also how its misuse can be detected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>